Guide to the Leonard R. Sayles Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Leonard R. Sayles Papers
1950-1962.
Sayles, Leonard R.
2.52 linear feet (6 manuscript boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079301
This collection contains research work which formed the basis of two of Sayles' books, The Local Union and Behavior of Industrial Work Groups. The collection includes interviews, case studies, and observation analyses.
History
Leonard Robert Sayles (b. 1926), Professor Emeritus of Business Administration, first came to Columbia University in 1956. The interviews in this collection represent the most intensive, nondirective explorations of manufacturing workers' relationships to their local unions and their families and jobs of the period. The interviews grew out of a foundation-sponsored (Grant Foundation) study of local unions directed by W.F. Whyte of Cornell University. Professor Sayles worked with George Strauss.
Scope and Content
Interviews and observation analyses which formed the basis of his two books, The Local Union and Behavior of Industrial Work Groups. Most of the interviews were conducted in the period 1950-1952 in local unions in upstate New York. The largest number are from the Allegheny Ludlum Steel Workers local in Dunkirk, N.Y. and they include descriptions of various kinds of meetings (grievance, union, political) as well as interviews and observation notes involving the membership, their families, and relationships with management. He also studied several other steel worker locals, less intensively, in upstate New York and western Pennsylvania. There are also interviews with a local of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers in Rochester, N.Y. (Michaels-Sterns factory); and copies of George Strauss' work in an American Can plant in Fairport, N.Y. and in a variety of building trades locals in the Rochester, N.Y. area.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in two series:
Series I: Allegheny Ludlum Steelworkers, 1950-1954
Series II: Other Interviews and Related Materials, 1950-1962
Subjects
Michaels-Stearns (Rochester, N.Y.); Allegheny Ludlum Industries.; Columbia University--Faculty.; Cornell University--Faculty.; United Steelworkers of America.; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America.; American Can Company.; William T. Grant Foundation.; Strauss, George, 1923-; Whyte, William Foote, 1914-2000.; Working class families.; Social groups.; Psychology, Industrial.; Industrial management.; Industrial relations.; Building trades--Employees--Labor unions--New York (State)--Rochester.; Clothing workers--Labor unions--New York (State)--Rochester.; Iron and steel workers--Labor unions--New York (State)--Dunkirk.; Iron and steel workers--Labor unions--Pennsylvania.; Labor union locals--New York (State)--Dunkirk.; Labor union locals--New York (State)--Rochester.; Clothing workers--New York (State)--Rochester.; Iron and steel workers--New York (State)--Dunkirk.; Iron and steel workers--Pennsylvania.; Container industry--New York (State)--Fairport.; Construction workers--New York (State)--Rochester.; Building trades--New York (State)--Rochester.; Industries--New York (State)--Rochester.; Industries--New York (State)--Dunkirk.; Industries--New York (State); Industries--Pennsylvania.; Industries--New York (State)--Fairport.; Interviews.; College teachers.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1977 M-77 Sayles, Leonard R. Gift
Finding aid in repository and online.
- Series I: Allegheny Ludlum Steelworkers, 1950-1954 Undated
  - Subseries I.1: General
    - Clippings, 1951-1953 Undated (Box 1)
  - Subseries I.2: Executive Board Studies, 1950-1952 Undated
    - Executive Board Study I, 1950-1951 Undated (Box 1)
    - Executive Board Study II, circa 1950-1951 (Box 1)
    - Executive Board Study III, 1950-1952 (Box 1)
  - Subseries I.3: Interviews, Case Studies, and Related Notes, 1950-1954 Undated
    - Centerless Grinders, 1951 (Box 1)
    - Fine Wire Mill
      - Correspondence--Joe Granto, Undated (Box 1)
      - Interviews, 1951 (Box 1)
      - Drafts and Notes, Undated (Box 1)
    - Hammershop
      - Interviews and Case Study, 1950-1951 (Box 1)
      - Analysis Notes, Undated (Box 1)
      - Writing, circa 1952 (Box 2)
    - Officers (Union), 1950-1952, (2 Folders) (Box 2)
    - Pennsylvania Unions--Local Chapters, 1951-1952 (Box 2)
    - Projective Pictures--Union and Plant, circa 1950s (Box 2)
      (Photographs of USA Local 2693, Dunkirk, New York (Allegheny Ludlum Plant) )
    - Union Administration--Statistics, circa 1950s (Box 2)
    - Union Meetings, 1950-1951, (2 Folders) (Box 2)
    - Study Reports, 1951 (Box 2)
    - Other Topics, 1950-1951 1954 Undated (Box 2)
- Series II: Other Interviews and Related Materials, 1950-1962 Undated
  - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (ACWA)
    - Interviews, 1953 (Box 3)
    - The Shop Chairman: Clothing Worker’s Study I & II, circa 1953, (2 Folders) (Box 3)
  - American Can Company
    - General, 1953 (Box 3)
    - Fairport International Association of Machinists
      - General, 1953 (Box 3)
      - Report, circa 1953 (Box 3)
    - In-Plant, 1952, (2 Folders) (Box 3)
    - Sayles, 1952-1953 (Box 3)
  - American Locomotive
    - Case, circa 1952 (Box 3)
      (Mostly clippings)
    - Interviews, 1950-1952, (2 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Building Trades
    - Rochester and Central Trades, 1952-1953 (Box 4)
    - Strauss Interviews, circa 1953 (Box 4)
  - Completed Reports--Union Study, 1950-1952 Undated (Box 4)
  - Incomplete Reports
    - Steward and Work Group Studies, 1950-1952 Undated (Box 4)
    - Leaders, Union Study, circa 1950s, (2 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Interviews--Miscellaneous, 1953, (2 Folders) (Box 4-5)
  - Miscellaneous
    - International Association of Machinists (IAM) Rochester District, Sm. Locals, 1952-1953 (Box 5)
    - Unions--Toy, Postal, Railroad, Office Workers, 1952-1953 (Box 5)
  - New Material for Industrial Relations 207 (Columbia University Graduate School of Business), 1960-1962 (Box 5)
  - Pfaudler, 1953 (Box 5)
  - Printing Trades--Rochester Typographers and Photoengravers, 1950-1952 (Box 5)
  - Prudential Insurance Agents, 1952-1953 (Box 5)
  - Rank and File, 1953, (2 Folders) (Box 5)
  - Relations with the National Union, circa 1950s (Box 6)
  - Sayles Research Project, 1954 Undated (Box 6)
    (Interviews)
  - Survey Methods--Fairport, Chicago, Elmira, 1950-1954 Undated (Box 6)
  - Unfiled Interviews, Primarily Union Research, 1951-1952 Undated (Box 6)
  - Union Community Activities, circa 1950s (Box 6)